[
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cd7geg3lvz1o#0",
    "title": "New round of ceasefire talks after Israel launches major offensive",
    "summary": "Hamas says its negotiators have opened a new round of talks aimed at ending the war, and all issues are on the table.",
    "date": "Sat, 17 May 2025 18:23:12 GMT",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Hamas",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "POSITIVE",
      "score": 0.7760469913482666
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cz0d31ydlg7o#0",
    "title": "Nine killed in Russian strike on civilian bus in Ukraine",
    "summary": "Another seven people are injured in Ukraine's north-eastern Sumy region, local officials say.",
    "date": "Sat, 17 May 2025 13:39:51 GMT",
    "entities": [
      [
        "seven",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Ukraine",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Sumy",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.9940047860145569
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c70nwr7zg7lo#0",
    "title": "Trump says he will call Putin on Monday to discuss stopping Ukraine 'bloodbath'",
    "summary": "The US president said he would also talk to Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky, and Nato leaders.",
    "date": "Sat, 17 May 2025 16:47:21 GMT",
    "entities": [
      [
        "US",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Ukrainian",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Volodymyr Zelensky",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Nato",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "POSITIVE",
      "score": 0.9667760133743286
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/czelprjn6z5o#0",
    "title": "Eurovision final 2025: Catch up with the top five favourites",
    "summary": "Meet the five artists who are tipped to take the Eurovision trophy, as Saturday's final draws near.",
    "date": "Fri, 16 May 2025 23:08:34 GMT",
    "entities": [
      [
        "five",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Eurovision",
        "EVENT"
      ],
      [
        "Saturday",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "POSITIVE",
      "score": 0.9993634819984436
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c70nw7v5ykyo#0",
    "title": "At least 21 dead after tornadoes sweep through US Midwest",
    "summary": "Kentucky and Missouri report severe injuries and deaths in storms that hit on Friday and Saturday.",
    "date": "Sat, 17 May 2025 17:17:17 GMT",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Kentucky",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Missouri",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Friday",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Saturday",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.9779618978500366
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/ce82vdgene7o#0",
    "title": "'To Easy LoL' - New Orleans jail break may have been inside job",
    "summary": "The inmates ripped a toilet from the wall and escaped through a hole before running across a highway.",
    "date": "Sat, 17 May 2025 02:26:01 GMT",
    "entities": [],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.998681366443634
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c4ge0xk4ld1o#0",
    "title": "US loses last perfect credit rating amid rising debt",
    "summary": "Moody's said successive US administrations had failed to reverse ballooning deficits and interest costs.",
    "date": "Sat, 17 May 2025 01:02:40 GMT",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Moody's",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "US",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.9982016086578369
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c8d14yyverro#1",
    "title": "Avalanche in Swiss Alps buries several people, police say",
    "summary": "A search and rescue operation is under way after an avalanche on the Eiger mountain in the Swiss Alps.",
    "date": "Sat, 17 May 2025 16:29:56 GMT",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Eiger",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "Alps",
        "LOC"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.9894940257072449
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cj42nvrkgzno#1",
    "title": "Cassie Ventura tells Diddy trial she would give back $20m to undo 'freak offs'",
    "summary": "The rapper's ex-girlfriend rejects defence suggestions that her accusations were financially motivated.",
    "date": "Sat, 17 May 2025 02:41:17 GMT",
    "entities": [],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.9942091703414917
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cvg7egyrk40o#1",
    "title": "Melania Trump statue goes missing in Slovenia",
    "summary": "The bronze depiction of the US First Lady is a replacement for a previous wooden version, which was set on fire in 2019.",
    "date": "Fri, 16 May 2025 18:00:52 GMT",
    "entities": [
      [
        "US",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "2019",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.9906705617904663
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cly3nyqx7xwo#1",
    "title": "Dizziness from hunger has become a constant, Gazans tell the BBC",
    "summary": "The BBC speaks to people in Gaza during a 10-week blockade on food, medical supplies and other aid.",
    "date": "Fri, 16 May 2025 17:08:21 GMT",
    "entities": [
      [
        "BBC",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Gaza",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "10-week",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.7838947176933289
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cpqelqpvpeqo#1",
    "title": "Five House Republicans stall Trump's 'big, beautiful' tax bill",
    "summary": "Lawmakers from the president's own party  joined all Democrats to reject a key domestic bill, demanding deeper budget cuts.",
    "date": "Sat, 17 May 2025 00:12:15 GMT",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Democrats",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.9765995144844055
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c0lnp3ny4wro#1",
    "title": "The poison paradox: How Australia's deadliest animals save lives",
    "summary": "The public antivenom programme saving lives in a place where, the joke goes, everything wants to kill you.",
    "date": "Fri, 16 May 2025 23:13:43 GMT",
    "entities": [],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.9756687879562378
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/crr70vykk0wo#1",
    "title": "Mexico accuses MrBeast of exploiting Mayan pyramids",
    "summary": "Authorities say they never allowed Jimmy Donaldson to film at pyramid heritage sites for profit.",
    "date": "Fri, 16 May 2025 21:58:45 GMT",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Jimmy Donaldson",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.9886294603347778
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cp85kg527p9o#1",
    "title": "Rushdie attacker sentenced to 25 years in prison",
    "summary": "Sir Salman was on a New York lecture stage, when he was stabbed multiple times in the face and neck leaving him partially blinded.",
    "date": "Fri, 16 May 2025 15:34:41 GMT",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Salman",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "New York",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.9956638216972351
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c8d19v3eygyo#1",
    "title": "Former Chad PM arrested over alleged links to deadly clash",
    "summary": "Masra's party the Transformers say their leader's detention took place \"outside of any known judicial procedure\".",
    "date": "Fri, 16 May 2025 16:29:07 GMT",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Masra",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Transformers",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.9981196522712708
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c308deylny1o#1",
    "title": "Russia jails Australian man for fighting alongside Ukraine",
    "summary": "Oscar Jenkins, 33, is sentenced to 13 years by a Russian-controlled court in eastern Ukraine.",
    "date": "Fri, 16 May 2025 15:04:43 GMT",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Oscar Jenkins",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "33",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "13 years",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Russian",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Ukraine",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.979949414730072
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cn7zvleen71o#1",
    "title": "Shock in Sweden at death of diplomat questioned for spying",
    "summary": "The man, described as a high-ranking diplomat, was arrested on Sunday and released on Wednesday.",
    "date": "Fri, 16 May 2025 18:53:32 GMT",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Sunday",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Wednesday",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.7471520304679871
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cgeg738rvdeo#1",
    "title": "ICC prosecutor steps aside until sexual misconduct probe ends",
    "summary": "Karim Khan takes leave until an investigation into allegations ends, the International Criminal Court says.",
    "date": "Fri, 16 May 2025 16:23:56 GMT",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Karim Khan",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "the International Criminal Court",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.9767241477966309
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c20x3d48509o#1",
    "title": "Gabon's ousted president and family freed after two years and fly to Angola",
    "summary": "Sylvia Bongo and her son was freed from prison last week despite facing charges of embezzling public funds.",
    "date": "Fri, 16 May 2025 17:01:41 GMT",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Sylvia Bongo",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "last week",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "POSITIVE",
      "score": 0.6116586327552795
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cj428kdn749o#1",
    "title": "Chris Brown remanded in custody over alleged club attack",
    "summary": "The American singer was arrested on Thursday over an alleged assault at a London nightclub in 2023.",
    "date": "Fri, 16 May 2025 13:08:28 GMT",
    "entities": [
      [
        "American",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Thursday",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "London",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "2023",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.9903958439826965
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c4gewwg1wlvo#1",
    "title": "US 'troubled' by humanitarian situation in Gaza, Rubio tells BBC",
    "summary": "The secretary of state's comments come as Israeli strikes across Gaza kill 114 people, according to hospitals and rescuers",
    "date": "Fri, 16 May 2025 03:22:20 GMT",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Israeli",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Gaza",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "114",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.9975638389587402
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/czxykqdlkego#1",
    "title": "Tigray party says ban threatens Ethiopia peace deal",
    "summary": "The TPLF fought a two-year civil war against the federal government, which ended in 2022.",
    "date": "Fri, 16 May 2025 09:39:49 GMT",
    "entities": [
      [
        "TPLF",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "two-year",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "2022",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.8655036687850952
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c20nk27lng3o#1",
    "title": "Ancient Indian skeleton gets a museum home six years after excavation",
    "summary": "The skeleton had been kept in a makeshift shed since its excavation in 2019 due to bureaucratic wrangling.",
    "date": "Fri, 16 May 2025 08:18:12 GMT",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2019",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.9989558458328247
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cvg7ekyvelpo#1",
    "title": "Colombian police arrest suspect in Peru mine workers' killings",
    "summary": "Thirteen men were kidnapped and killed at a gold mine in Pataz district earlier in May.",
    "date": "Fri, 16 May 2025 04:41:39 GMT",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Thirteen",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Pataz",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "May",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.9851764440536499
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c780xn5p72jo#1",
    "title": "Israel qualifies for Eurovision final after protests disrupt rehearsal",
    "summary": "Israel's Yuval Raphael makes it to the final, alongside acts from Austria and Malta.",
    "date": "Thu, 15 May 2025 22:34:03 GMT",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Israel",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Yuval Raphael",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Austria",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Malta",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "POSITIVE",
      "score": 0.9995878338813782
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cvgnp103zr9o#1",
    "title": "LA 2028 Olympics plans air taxi service for spectators",
    "summary": "The aircraft still aren't commercially approved but could offer a way around Los Angeles' notoriously poor traffic.",
    "date": "Fri, 16 May 2025 02:56:36 GMT",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Los Angeles'",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.992938756942749
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/clyv789ejgxo#2",
    "title": "Trump's frantic week of peace brokering hints at what he really wants",
    "summary": "After seven breathless days of diplomatic hurly burly, we have a clearer idea of the US president's global ideology - and the limits of his 'art of a deal'.",
    "date": "Fri, 16 May 2025 23:01:32 GMT",
    "entities": [
      [
        "seven breathless days",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "US",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "POSITIVE",
      "score": 0.9656442999839783
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cvgv445jqr1o#2",
    "title": "Of opium, fire temples, and sarees: A peek into the world of India's dwindling Parsis",
    "summary": "The Alpaiwala Museum in Mumbai city traces the origins and history of the fast-dwindling Parsi community.",
    "date": "Fri, 16 May 2025 23:32:14 GMT",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Alpaiwala Museum",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Mumbai",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Parsi",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "POSITIVE",
      "score": 0.9973300695419312
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cn8zxn9xg2ro#2",
    "title": "Polish voters set for tight presidential race after 10 years of Duda",
    "summary": "Sunday's first-round is expected to set up a run-off between Warsaw's liberal mayor and a conservative historian.",
    "date": "Fri, 16 May 2025 15:50:16 GMT",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Sunday",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Warsaw",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.9936829805374146
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c20x395pvvjo#2",
    "title": "Is Britain really inching back towards the EU?",
    "summary": "The summit between the UK and EU on 19 May will be the first since Brexit - the very idea of it has polarised opinions",
    "date": "Thu, 15 May 2025 23:43:30 GMT",
    "entities": [
      [
        "UK",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "EU",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "19 May",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Brexit",
        "EVENT"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.9584775567054749
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c98p3eple9eo#2",
    "title": "'I didn't come here for fun' - Afrikaner defends refugee status in US",
    "summary": "Charl Kleinhaus tells the BBC he had no choice but to leave his farm in South Africa after receiving death threats.",
    "date": "Thu, 15 May 2025 22:28:58 GMT",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Charl Kleinhaus",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "BBC",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "South Africa",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.9984409213066101
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c9wg5pg1xp5o#2",
    "title": "Is there a genocide of white South Africans as Trump claims?",
    "summary": "US President Donald Trump says a genocide is taking place in South Africa, a claim a judge dismissed as \"imaginary\".",
    "date": "Fri, 16 May 2025 11:19:02 GMT",
    "entities": [
      [
        "US",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Donald Trump",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "South Africa",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.9906781911849976
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cgmj7l0lne3o#2",
    "title": "How India and Pakistan share one of the world's most dangerous borders",
    "summary": "Living along the LoC - the volatile India-Pakistan border - means life in a fragile limbo between war and peace.",
    "date": "Thu, 15 May 2025 23:32:50 GMT",
    "entities": [
      [
        "LoC",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "India",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "POSITIVE",
      "score": 0.9911993145942688
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cly3nw938deo#2",
    "title": "Valeria Marquez: Who was the Mexican influencer killed live on TikTok?",
    "summary": "Prosecutors say they are treating the killing of 23-year-old Valeria Marquez as a femicide.",
    "date": "Fri, 16 May 2025 00:57:16 GMT",
    "entities": [
      [
        "23-year-old",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Valeria Marquez",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.9904776811599731
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c628q8w7ej3o#2",
    "title": "Blank questions, power cuts and a suicide: Nigeria's exams fiasco",
    "summary": "Nearly 80% of the 1.9 million students who sat the exams did not get high enough marks to get into university.",
    "date": "Thu, 15 May 2025 16:56:39 GMT",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Nearly 80%",
        "PERCENT"
      ],
      [
        "1.9 million",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.9978280663490295
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cg5v2rjp84ro#2",
    "title": "BBC joins Gaza children as they are evacuated to Jordan for treatment",
    "summary": "The BBC's Fergal Keane accompanies children being evacuated from Gaza on their journey to Jordan.",
    "date": "Thu, 15 May 2025 05:44:20 GMT",
    "entities": [
      [
        "BBC",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Fergal Keane",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Gaza",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Jordan",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "POSITIVE",
      "score": 0.9820458292961121
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c8e6wj07xlno#2",
    "title": "Beginning of the end? Ukraine's front-line soldiers eye Russia talks with hope",
    "summary": "There is cautious optimism in eastern Ukraine as talks are set to take place in Istanbul.",
    "date": "Wed, 14 May 2025 21:09:37 GMT",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Ukraine",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Istanbul",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "POSITIVE",
      "score": 0.9913255572319031
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/ce82ene10p0o#2",
    "title": "Construction sites appear in Gaza ahead of Israeli-US aid plan rejected by UN, images show",
    "summary": "Satellite images show building at sites in south Gaza after US says controversial Israeli aid plan to proceed.",
    "date": "Thu, 15 May 2025 09:54:59 GMT",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Gaza",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "US",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Israeli",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.9881870150566101
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c3v5r1erdpgo#2",
    "title": "Why India could not stop IMF bailout to Pakistan",
    "summary": "As one of 25 member groups on the IMF board, India's influence at the fund is limited, say experts.",
    "date": "Wed, 14 May 2025 23:48:46 GMT",
    "entities": [
      [
        "one",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "25",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "IMF",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "India",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.9994410872459412
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cp3q129gpe4o#2",
    "title": "Do Afrikaners want to take Trump up on his South African refugee offer?",
    "summary": "Claims of a white genocide are widely discredited, so how do Afrikaners feel about Trump's claims – and offer of refugee status?",
    "date": "Thu, 15 May 2025 01:43:02 GMT",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Afrikaners",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Trump",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.9959189295768738
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c1e679vn6yqo#2",
    "title": "Meet the 'invisible crew' who have 35 seconds to prevent a Eurovision blunder",
    "summary": "Find out how Eurovision gets one act off the stage and another one in place in under a minute.",
    "date": "Thu, 15 May 2025 00:10:44 GMT",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Eurovision",
        "EVENT"
      ],
      [
        "one",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "under a minute",
        "TIME"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.9965257048606873
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c5y2dgep4zzo#2",
    "title": "What did Erik and Lyle Menendez do and when could they be released?",
    "summary": "On Tuesday, a Los Angeles judge reduced Lyle and Erik's murder sentence, making them eligible for parole.",
    "date": "Wed, 14 May 2025 11:20:29 GMT",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Tuesday",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Los Angeles",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Lyle",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Erik",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "POSITIVE",
      "score": 0.5916476845741272
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/clygv2dj78zo#2",
    "title": "'Go back to Ukraine': War refugees complain of abuse in Poland",
    "summary": "Dozens say they have been abused in public, bullied in schools and seen increasing xenophobic material online.",
    "date": "Wed, 14 May 2025 05:00:07 GMT",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Dozens",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.991419792175293
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cp857gryxn1o#2",
    "title": "The heartbeat of a billion: What Virat Kohli meant to India",
    "summary": "Legendary India batter Virat Kohli announced retirement from international Test cricket on Monday.",
    "date": "Tue, 13 May 2025 23:16:31 GMT",
    "entities": [
      [
        "India",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Virat Kohli",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Monday",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.9583393931388855
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cewdl20d8lxo#2",
    "title": "El Chapo & Deputy Jesus - why Kenya's president has so many nicknames",
    "summary": "William Ruto has the uncanny ability to attract numerous alternative handles, most are unflattering.",
    "date": "Tue, 13 May 2025 23:31:41 GMT",
    "entities": [
      [
        "William Ruto",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.8520706295967102
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c2e373yzndro#2",
    "title": "How real is the risk of nuclear war between India and Pakistan?",
    "summary": "Recent hostilities were a reminder of how easily a crisis could escalate into catastrophe.",
    "date": "Tue, 13 May 2025 23:35:23 GMT",
    "entities": [],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.9749955534934998
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/videos/c20x1w9xq4po#3",
    "title": "Ros Atkins on... how world leaders are responding to Israel's blockade of Gaza",
    "summary": "The BBC's Analysis Editor Ros Atkins looks at how world leaders are responding to Israel's blockade of Gaza.",
    "date": "Sat, 17 May 2025 00:06:01 GMT",
    "entities": [
      [
        "BBC",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Ros Atkins",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Israel",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Gaza",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "POSITIVE",
      "score": 0.9882645606994629
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/videos/c2d54g6rkkyo#3",
    "title": "How Diddy's lawyers used 'freak off' texts against Cassie",
    "summary": "The BBC's Nada Tawfik explains what happened when the text messages were brought up in court.",
    "date": "Fri, 16 May 2025 21:33:01 GMT",
    "entities": [
      [
        "BBC",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Nada Tawfik",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.9950711727142334
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/videos/cx2qe7lekqlo#3",
    "title": "Huge fire engulfs historic plantation house in Louisiana",
    "summary": "Flames ripped through Nottoway House, destroying much of structure, which was built in 1859.",
    "date": "Fri, 16 May 2025 22:47:19 GMT",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Nottoway House",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "1859",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.997340738773346
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/videos/cd0lj4rnre9o#3",
    "title": "Watch: UK surgeon shares footage from Gaza hospital after deadly Israeli strike",
    "summary": "Tuesday's strike killed 28 people, the Hamas-run civil defence said. Israel says it was a precise strike on Hamas.",
    "date": "Thu, 15 May 2025 21:34:27 GMT",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Tuesday",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "28",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Hamas",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Israel",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Hamas",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.9718919992446899
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.bbc.com/news/videos/c8re5134k0yo#3",
    "title": "Watch: Wildlife dyed blue in São Paulo chemical spill",
    "summary": "City officials say they are acting to rescue and save the lives of the affected animals.",
    "date": "Fri, 16 May 2025 02:13:28 GMT",
    "entities": [],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.6137290596961975
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.aljazeera.com/?t=1747492910",
    "title": "Hamas says new Gaza truce talks under way as Israel expands ground assault",
    "summary": "Israel and Hamas confirm indirect talks being held in Qatar as Israel expands ground offensive, killing dozens.",
    "date": "Sat, 17 May 2025 16:23:28 +0000",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Israel",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Hamas",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Qatar",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Israel",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "dozens",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.9917305111885071
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.aljazeera.com/?t=1747483085",
    "title": "At least 21 dead after storms hit US states of Missouri and Kentucky",
    "summary": "The storms are part of a severe weather system sweeping across the Midwest, leaving thousands without power.",
    "date": "Sat, 17 May 2025 13:27:50 +0000",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Midwest",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "thousands",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.9995588660240173
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.aljazeera.com/?t=1747476032",
    "title": "Iran’s leaders slam Trump for ‘disgraceful’ remarks during Middle East tour",
    "summary": "The pushback comes after the US president accused Tehran&#039;s leadership of being &#039;corrupt and ineffective&#039;.",
    "date": "Sat, 17 May 2025 12:22:42 +0000",
    "entities": [
      [
        "US",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.9954856038093567
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.aljazeera.com/?t=1747469858",
    "title": "Seven European nations urge Israel to ‘reverse its current policy’ on Gaza",
    "summary": "Israel has halted the entry of food, medication and all other essentials into the Palestinian territory since March 2.",
    "date": "Sat, 17 May 2025 11:37:59 +0000",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Israel",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Palestinian",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "March 2",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.9977952241897583
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.aljazeera.com/?t=1747477420",
    "title": "Trump’s moment in the Middle East",
    "summary": "Dissecting the spectacle and substance of Trump’s Middle East tour.",
    "date": "Sat, 17 May 2025 11:24:32 +0000",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Trump",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Middle East",
        "LOC"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.9622454047203064
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.aljazeera.com/?t=1747233810",
    "title": "Poland presidential election 2025: Polls, results, contenders",
    "summary": "Poles head to the polls to elect their next president as incumbent Duda&#039;s second term comes to an end.",
    "date": "Sat, 17 May 2025 11:16:45 +0000",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Poles",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "second",
        "ORDINAL"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.9961898326873779
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.aljazeera.com/?t=1747468866",
    "title": "Everton vs Southampton: Goodison Park stages final Premier League match",
    "summary": "Everton play their final Premier League match at Goodison Park on Sunday at a venue steeped in history and tradition.",
    "date": "Sat, 17 May 2025 11:09:00 +0000",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Everton",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Premier League",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Goodison Park",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "Sunday",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "POSITIVE",
      "score": 0.9980807304382324
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.aljazeera.com/?t=1747470641",
    "title": "UK police charge three Iranians with suspected espionage",
    "summary": "The men were charged with engaging in conduct likely to assist a foreign intelligence service, police said.",
    "date": "Sat, 17 May 2025 10:42:10 +0000",
    "entities": [],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.9728173613548279
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.aljazeera.com/?t=1747463884",
    "title": "Libyan ministers resign as protesters call for government to step down",
    "summary": "Police officer killed as the country sees renewed deadly clashes in the aftermath of the killing of a militia commander.",
    "date": "Sat, 17 May 2025 09:51:55 +0000",
    "entities": [],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.9901586174964905
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.aljazeera.com/?t=1747402450",
    "title": "Q&A: Botswana’s Letsile Tebogo on his Olympic triumph; African sprinters",
    "summary": "Tebogo talks to Al Jazeera about breaking the American and Jamaican dominance, and the future of sprinting in Africa.",
    "date": "Sat, 17 May 2025 09:21:38 +0000",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Tebogo",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Al Jazeera",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "American",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Jamaican",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Africa",
        "LOC"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "POSITIVE",
      "score": 0.9941283464431763
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.aljazeera.com/?t=1747465317",
    "title": "Arab League calls for funds to rebuild Gaza at summit in Baghdad",
    "summary": "The war on Palestinian territory dominated the summit, especially after Israel approves plans to expand its offensive.",
    "date": "Sat, 17 May 2025 09:02:55 +0000",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Palestinian",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Israel",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "POSITIVE",
      "score": 0.9810386300086975
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.aljazeera.com/?t=1747467772",
    "title": "Israel’s Gaza ‘disengagement’ that paved the way for conquest",
    "summary": "The Israeli withdrawal from Gaza in 2005 was not a concession. It was a strategic move to thwart Palestinian statehood.",
    "date": "Sat, 17 May 2025 08:18:54 +0000",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Israeli",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Gaza",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "2005",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Palestinian",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.9975741505622864
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.aljazeera.com/?t=1747464847",
    "title": "Knicks oust Celtics in Game 6 playoffs, make Eastern Conference finals",
    "summary": "New York&#039;s 38-point victory against Boston Celtics in Game 6 was the largest win in Knicks playoff history.",
    "date": "Sat, 17 May 2025 07:48:28 +0000",
    "entities": [
      [
        "New York&#039;s 38",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Boston Celtics",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Game 6",
        "EVENT"
      ],
      [
        "Knicks",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "POSITIVE",
      "score": 0.9996143579483032
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.aljazeera.com/?t=1747462419",
    "title": "Trump says he will call Putin, Zelenskyy to discuss Ukraine ‘bloodbath’",
    "summary": "The US leader says he will phone the Russian president, followed by his Ukrainian counterpart and NATO allies on Monday.",
    "date": "Sat, 17 May 2025 07:44:57 +0000",
    "entities": [
      [
        "US",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Russian",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Ukrainian",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "NATO",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Monday",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.9608674049377441
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.aljazeera.com/?t=1747394100",
    "title": "‘Exploding inequality’: The fight for the hearts and minds of Poland’s left",
    "summary": "The left-wing contenders in Sunday’s presidential election are expected to perform better this time - but not much.",
    "date": "Sat, 17 May 2025 07:40:59 +0000",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Sunday",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.9987698197364807
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.aljazeera.com/?t=1747388256",
    "title": "Thousands of Palestinians flee north Gaza amid intensified Israeli attacks",
    "summary": "Israel kills at least 115 Palestinians since Friday as it intensifies bombardment amid widespread forced starvation.",
    "date": "Sat, 17 May 2025 07:00:26 +0000",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Israel",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "at least 115",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Palestinians",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Friday",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.9984917640686035
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.aljazeera.com/?t=1747450052",
    "title": "Russia-Ukraine war: List of key events, day 1,178",
    "summary": "These are the key events on day 1,178 of Russia’s war on Ukraine.",
    "date": "Sat, 17 May 2025 03:36:00 +0000",
    "entities": [
      [
        "day 1,178",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Russia",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Ukraine",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "POSITIVE",
      "score": 0.9895080327987671
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.aljazeera.com/?t=1747295186",
    "title": "Malaysia’s ‘fish hunters’ target invasive species, one catch at a time",
    "summary": "Invasive species are an issue the world over, and waterways in mega-biodiverse Malaysia are threatened by imported fish.",
    "date": "Sat, 17 May 2025 01:12:14 +0000",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Malaysia",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.9974773526191711
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.aljazeera.com/?t=1747436373",
    "title": "US announces first ‘terrorism’ charges for supporting a Mexican cartel",
    "summary": "Immigration and Customs Enforcement has accused a Mexican woman of furnishing a cartel with grenades and other weapons.",
    "date": "Sat, 17 May 2025 00:16:08 +0000",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Immigration and Customs Enforcement",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Mexican",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.9930248260498047
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.aljazeera.com/?t=1747435484",
    "title": "Moody’s strips US government of top credit rating",
    "summary": "Moody&#039;s cited rising debt saying US had repeatedly failed to end the trend of large annual fiscal deficits and interest.",
    "date": "Fri, 16 May 2025 23:23:50 +0000",
    "entities": [
      [
        "US",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "annual",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.9861306548118591
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.aljazeera.com/?t=1747432563",
    "title": "US Supreme Court blocks the Trump administration’s use of Alien Enemies Act",
    "summary": "The court majority once again upheld a ruling that migrants were entitled to due process before their deportations.",
    "date": "Fri, 16 May 2025 23:12:37 +0000",
    "entities": [],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "POSITIVE",
      "score": 0.98581463098526
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.aljazeera.com/?t=1747432183",
    "title": "Has Donald Trump taken US-Gulf relations to a new era?",
    "summary": "US President Donald Trump has concluded his three-nation tour of the Gulf region.",
    "date": "Fri, 16 May 2025 22:37:14 +0000",
    "entities": [
      [
        "US",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Donald Trump",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "three",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Gulf",
        "LOC"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "POSITIVE",
      "score": 0.9981648325920105
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.aljazeera.com/?t=1747422604",
    "title": "European leaders consult Trump to align response to Russia-Ukraine talks",
    "summary": "European leaders speak to US president after Russia-Ukraine talks fail to achieve major breakthrough.",
    "date": "Fri, 16 May 2025 22:24:45 +0000",
    "entities": [
      [
        "European",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "US",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Russia",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "POSITIVE",
      "score": 0.6112946271896362
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.aljazeera.com/?t=1747417269",
    "title": "‘I cannot stand by’: Former ambassador denounces Ukraine shift under Trump",
    "summary": "Bridget Brink has written an op-ed accusing Trump of putting &#039;pressure on the victim&#039;, Ukraine, instead of Russia.",
    "date": "Fri, 16 May 2025 21:54:37 +0000",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Bridget Brink",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Trump",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Ukraine",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Russia",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.9741849303245544
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "https://www.aljazeera.com/?t=1747431206",
    "title": "‘No soap, no morphine’: Gaza volunteer on life under intensified bombing",
    "summary": "Gaza volunteer calls Israel’s intensified bombardment “shocking” as Palestinians face severe food and medical shortages.",
    "date": "Fri, 16 May 2025 21:35:33 +0000",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Gaza",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Israel",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Palestinians",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ],
    "events": [],
    "sentiment": {
      "label": "NEGATIVE",
      "score": 0.995360791683197
    }
  }
]